today i want to share with you my
experience learning english i learned
the foundations of english the way many
people do sometimes they learn it at
school sometimes they go to a private
academy or they have a private tutor i
don't think i was very good at it back
then i started to become comfortable in
english when instead of trying to learn
english i used english to learn how to
code this way learning the english
language wasn't the goal
english was the vehicle that i used to
accomplish my bigger goal which was to
learn how to program when i was learning
to code none of the documentations or
tutorials that i wanted to follow were
in my native language instead they were
all in english which was really annoying
but looking back i am grateful that that
was the case learning to code in english
meant that as i was learning to code i
was practicing english in the background
some people say that to really
internalize and dominate a language you
actually have to start thinking
in that language i think that's true
because i realized that by learning to
code in english i was starting to think
in english by understanding programming
concepts in english i became more
comfortable with english if i saw
programming concepts like abstractions
imperative code declarative code dot
typing type complexity i realized that
it was better to understand these
concepts in english than rather than
trying to look for a translation i
really think that if you're learning to
code if you do it in english some things
are actually going to be easier to
understand because most of the time the
clues of what things do in programming
are on the name itself for example a
concept like event bubbling in
javascript will be easier understood if
you know what event and bubble mean when
we are learning to code we are also
going to be faced with many errors and
if we google those errors in english it
is going to be a very high percentage
that we're going to find a solution for
our error rather than if we try to find
the solution to the error in a different
community in our native language because
for better or worse all these error
messages are also in english the people
that are facing those error messages and
the people that will give you the
solution they also speak english if you
think about it if you use english you
open the door to such a huge amount of
people that you can interact with in
communities for developers for example
in stack overflow you can find answers
for almost anything already where you
can actually talk and make developer
friends and you can see what the news
are in the developer world which are all
in english also if we think about it for
better or worse the programming
languages that will give us a job are
all written in english the concepts and
the words of our trade our industry they
are all in english the internet itself
was built speaking english python for
example was created by a dutch person
but python is in english or linus is
from finland but linux is still in
english the documentation of most open
source projects that we are going to be
using in our daily job are also written
initially in english
and the new things that are happening in
our industry are all happening in
english for example if you look at the
cryptocurrency industry or what's going
on with nfts all these things are
happening in english if we want to be
where the innovation is and where people
are building exciting and cool and
different things the way we can interact
with those people in the way that they
are sharing their ideas is all in
english also after the pandemic there
are more and more companies that are
hiring remote workers when you work
remotely they don't care about how you
look like or where you live they care
about your code and your english because
you have to be able to communicate with
the team so if you are learning to code
i would really really advise you to
learn to code in english it would help
you a lot as a developer to understand
all these concepts that are named using
english words and also it will make your
english better instead of making english
the goal as i said before you can make
english a vehicle to accomplish a
different goal and by doing this you're
going to be practicing english in the
background without even noticing as a
beginner you are going to have many
questions as well and you will be able
to access all these answers and
questions if you do it in english rather
than in our own native languages if you
are already a developer and you think
that you could improve your english a
little bit i really encourage you to do
so it will make you more competitive in
your career you will be able to apply
for different jobs overseas and in
different kinds of companies and also
you will be able to improve your craft
as a developer we have to be careful
with the lies that we tell ourselves
just like some people say that they are
not good at math some people say i'm not
good at english maybe because somebody
made fun of them because of their accent
or maybe because they cannot pronounce a
word very well the first step is of
course believing in ourselves i think
that if you already can talk to machines
using java using c plus plus using c
whatever you're using learning english
would be a piece of cake but also we
have to be careful if we're trying to be
too perfect i personally think that if
you have an accent when speaking english
you should be proud of that i am proud
to have an accent because it's mine and
it shows people that i'm not a native
english speaker but still i went outside
of my comfort zone to learn a new
language maybe when i finally start
making videos a hundred percent in
google i am sure i'm going to have a
webinar accent and i'm completely fine
with that before i go i know i might
sound a little bit dismissive of how
hard it is for people to learn english
depending on the country they are from
if you speak italian or spanish like me
it's going to be very very easy for you
to learn english because our languages
are very close to english we share the
same grammar we share the same shapes in
a way we share the same alphabet but i
know that if you come from korea it's
going to be very hard to learn english
because of how far away these languages
are since i started studying korean i
was able to really appreciate how far
away
english and korean are from each other
is crazy this has really made me respect
and admire the koreans that are studying
and speaking in english even more
because i know now how hard it is to
learn if you had to ask me what is the
number one skill that i believe changed
my life for the better i would say that
learning english has been more
beneficial for my life than actually
learning to code if you speak english
doors will open for you not only
career-wise but life-wise you will be
able to travel more you will be able to
meet more people you will be able to
change your opinions after seeing
different points of view your mind will
expand in ways you cannot imagine that's
it for this video thank you as always
for watching i hope that you like this
kind of videos a little bit more
personal it's not about code let me know
if you like this side of me i guess in
the comments i don't have an english
course to announce i just wanted to
share this opinion with you because it's
a question that i get asked a lot if you
want to learn to code as you know you
can do it for free you can click the
link below and i will see you there
where we're going to learn to code from
javascript to react to react native to
go many many things thank you as always
for watching stay happy stay free eat
kimchi kamzamita salan hayo see you on
the next one
ciao